Smit Patel

Full Stack Engineer

Winnipeg, Canada

△ smitpatelx.com

☐ github.com/smitpatelx

With over 4.5 years of experience working in the Software Industry with proficiencies in Javascript(ES6), Typescript, Python, GO, PHP, UI/UX, C#, Java and many more, I continue to be a driving force for my team. Seeking full time placement where I could deepen my existing knowledge and pick up on new rising tech.

Experience

Lead Full Stack Engineer

Datomar Labs Inc.

Mar 2022 - May 2023

Winnipeg, Manitoba

- O Work with the business unit to understand, develop or refine requirements for projects within the company.
- Manage UX and UI design and/or work with outside design stakeholders to ensure high quality design is implemented.
- -O- Build ci-cd pipelines, dockerize applications, setup projects, develop independently, research emerging technologies.
- Make use of technologies like React/Nextjs, MUI, Typescript, GO, PostgreSQL, Vuejs, Wordpress, TailwindCss, Headless UI and Framer Motion.
- -O- Work on optimizing, refactoring, analysis of code. Ensure good quality of testing and setup logging & analytics.

Software Engineer

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

Farmlink Marketing Solutions

Winnipeg, Manitoba

- -O- Design, code and debug software applications using front end frameworks and enterprise applications
- **-O-** Performing Software analysis, requirements gathering, software reviews, identification of code metrics, system risk analysis, and software reliability analysis.
- -O- Writing tests, migrations, end-to-end feature testing and development using Python, Django, Postgres, Vuejs.
- -O- Mentor junior devs to meet code quality standards.
- -O- UI & UX design using figma, keeping up with latest technologies, design UI animations using leaflet and keyframes.

Director of Web Development

June 2020 - Jan 2021

Blabbly

Winnipeg, Manitoba

- -O- Perform web development tasks utilizing PHP/NodeJs Framework, Web Services, and SQL Server.
- Design and evolve highly interactive user interfaces and HTML prototypes for web and email initiatives.

Skills

Programming Languages

Javascript (ES6), Typescript, Python, GO, PHP, C#, Java

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Nextjs, TainwindCss, MUI, Vuetify, Vuejs, Svelte, Framer Motion, Redux, Vuex, SCSS

Database & Servers

MySql, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Firebase, Apache, Nginx, Linux, Docker, AWS, GCS, Heroku

Other

Git, JSP, CertBot, Bootstrap, Foundation, Ulkit

Tools & Softwares

AdobeXD, Figma, AdobeAi, SEO, Agile, Jira, Sentry, Gleap, VS Code, Go Land, Blender

Education

Computer Programmer

Durham College Oshawa, ON 2017-2020

Certifications

- MVC with Laravel
- OOP with C#
- Deployment with Docker
- Accessibility for web
- Advance CSS and Key Frames
- -- Reactis Advance Concepts
- Vuejs Master Class
- Nextjs FullStack
- Websocket for modern Apps
- -- Flutter mobile development

V1.5

Experience

Director of Web Development

June 2020 - Jan 2021 Winnipeg, Manitoba

Blabbly

- -O- Work as part of an agile team fostering teamwork, mentoring others, and striving for overall excellence.
- -O- Develop & Design custom solutions like plugins, theme & CI-CD pipeline for corporate clients.
- -O- Setup C-Panels, Configure Docker Mail Serves & Micro-services using Kubernetes for various applications.

Full-Stack Developer

Oct 2017 - Mar 2020

Self-Employed

Toronto, Ontario

- -O- Building Backend API using Node.js, PHP, ASP.NET, JAVA to serve requests and server content on front-end.
- -O- Setup containers on Debian based systems to host Nginx and Apache servers.
- -O- Setup docker containers for Postgres, MySql and MongoDB to improve stability and scalability of projects.
- -O- Develop UI/UX by using tools like AdobeXD, Figma and collobrate with other developers to improve design.
- -O- Prototype responsive websites using Nuxt.js; design interactions using SCSS, TailwindCss and BootStrap.

Projects I worked on

Real-Estate Listing - Avenest

https://github.com/smitpatelx/avenest





(Vue.js) (PHP) (TailwindCss)

Humn Pharma - ECommerce

https://humnpharma.com









Open Source plugin for wordpress

Code: https://github.com/smitpatelx/robust-user-search/ **Plugin**: https://wordpress.org/plugins/robust-user-search/

PHP Vue.js

Signature Generator for emails

https://github.com/smitpatelx/employee-onboarding-form



(Nuxt.js) (Vue.js) (TailwindCss)

Lyberal Music

Blogging Site

(Laravel) (Vue.js)

https://github.com/smitpatelx/4unaturalistic_gridsome

https://github.com/smitpatelx/employee-onboarding-form

(Gridsome) (Wordpress) (Algolia)

Employee Onboarding Site

Real-Time Chat Application https://github.com/smitpatelx/socket_chat

https://www.lyberalmusic.com/

Nodejs Vue.js Socket.io

(Wordpress)

Marketing and Planning solutions for farmers

https://www.farmlinksolutions.ca/what-is-grainfox/

Django Vue.js Leafletjs Fusion Charts

DEUTZ - Build & Price tool for automobile industry

https://deutz.preproduction.datomar.dev/build-price/

React Next.js GO MUI TypeScript

Mufflr - A car buying service

https://app.mufflr.ca

React Next.js

Tailwindcss GO

Heroku

Brownie Points

https://browniepoints.club/

Vue.js SCSS Bulma